<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Away With Religion</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Away With Religion</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.155.2</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:36:58 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In the Beginning - Why I Am No Longer A Christian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 10:36:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/in-the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Bible be true, the New Testament differs greatly from the Old Testament in its teachings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 39 books of the OT were consolidated in Rome, leaving out a part of Hebrew history “uncanonised”.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Important books are Jubilees, Enoch and Jasher. These might have their errors (translational or human authorship errors), but they contain info about the promised land (sub-Saharan Africa) and its inhabitants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christianity is based purely on the NT teachings.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even references from the OT are only but typological.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The NT has a lot in common with the writings of Flavius Josephus (Jewish Wars, Jewish Antiquities).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Josephus was a Jew (Pharisee, Sadducee, Essene) by descent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He was later adopted into the imperial family by Vespasian after “correctly predicting” the latter’s ascendence into power, from general to emperor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The NT was written (mainly) by Titus Flavius, and Jesus is himself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christianity has always been a tool of control, as with the case with other religions.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judaism, derived from the Hebrew culture, added Talmudic practices to it and became a force, especially later in Eastern Europe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Islam, with the Ottomans and caliphates of the Arab world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hence the reason politicians will comfortably use the tool to their advantage; it was designed for that purpose anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant Christian themes are submission, obedience to authorities, accepting humiliation and not seeking vengeance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christianity was introduced to the continent through schools, hospitals and other social amenities, luring the leaders of the day into conversion.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Later, the colonialists had an easier time dealing with an already brainwashed people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To date, most sub-Saharan Africans are out of touch with core cultural practices. Christianity has taught them that most of the practices are evil and should be done away with; a softening of the mind towards an acceptance of strange/foreign policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes, there’s no rapture, no occupying heaven, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
